welcome to meditating with John gravity
I'm a cognitive psychologist and a
cognitive scientist at the University of
Toronto where I teach and scientifically
study mindfulness and related phenomena
like insight flow mystical experience
transformative experience higher states
of consciousness a cultivation of wisdom
the aspiration towards enlightenment
I've been practicing the past of
meditation and meta contemplation Tai
Chi Chuan and she come for over 29 years
and teaching and professionally for
close to close to 20 years you're
joining us for the first time welcome
but you should know that you've joined a
ongoing progressive course the
introductory course is done and if you
want to catch up while not please check
the links in the description of this
video and you can find all the previous
lessons right now we're moving into more
advanced techniques every other Monday
is a Dharma day in which I will teach a
practice in principle that builds on all
the previous practices and principles
and adds to them enriches them in some
fashion it would be very helpful to me
if you liked this video stream that will
raise its profile in the youtube search
algorithm and help me to reach more
people during these difficult times with
this I believe strongly believe very
helpful ecology practices on the
teaching field at the end of every
lesson and at the end of every set does
Monday through Fridays Tuesdays through
Friday's were just sitting there's
always Q&A please keep the qat limited
to questions about this course if you
have more general questions please call
them to my live stream youtube general
Q&A that we hold every third Friday at 3
p.m. Eastern Time so let's review what
we did yesterday last Monday was a
Dharma day we talked about a way of
actually doing Dharma part of the Buddha
the Dhamma
a way of reading drawn from the
Neoplatonic Christian tradition this is
called Lexi Oh Davina you picked to tap
two sources of text some sacred poetry
some sacred prose I'm going to review
the process but also if you check the
notes and yet from yesterday's class
from yesterday's lesson on lectio Divina
it's entitled lectio Divina you'll find
that these stages of the practice
described they'll also find a list of
books that are helpful so for each text
you first set your intention you set
yourself to get into a state of
reverence and reading for transformation
trying to resonate with the text once
you set that then what you do is you
have it right enacted engagement you
read the text aloud you try to associate
with it you try to feel it you really
just let it resonate in you and what
you're trying to do is notice anything
in the text that catches your attention
calls out to you even if you don't
understand why something that grabs you
then you move into the emotional
embodiment the second stage of the
process well you do that was allowing
yourself to you know associated memories
and especially emotions come up and then
any of any imagery any gestures any
postures that come up in connection with
the reading there might be imagery
actually from within the reading you
don't you engage in them and magically
imaginal e doesn't mean you don't engage
them inside your head you project them
as if you were interacting and enacting
them in the world
this is embodied then you move to the
existential ethics what would it be like
to live your life in this way of seeing
and being comprehensively what would it
be like to live this way what would that
perspective of knowing as you're sort of
default setting in the world what would
that be like and then that leads into
the fourth and final stage the ecstatic
which means to stand beyond yourself I'm
eternal well let's be within that lived
spective right within that worldview
what would be disclosed about the world
and correspondingly what would be
demanded from you in order to conform to
that realization so you do that with the
poetry you repeat the same process with
the prose and when you're doing the
prose it'll happen usually spontaneously
this is called sin Tamara that what
happened with the poetry and prose we'll
talk to each other let them talk to each
other as a way of talking to you and
then we're done express some gratitude
and some resolution that you'll try to
remember and we realize what you have
what has happened to you throughout the
reading remember sometimes what comes
right isn't a full-blown insight it
might be an inkling it might be feeling
it might just be a sense of
reorientation there's a wide continuum
of responses you get from Mexico to view
now finally recommend that you do let's
hear Davina after you do a sitting right
after so I hope you have your ebooks
your text chosen from yesterday and I
hope you practice it a bit yesterday do
this sit we will do the Q&A and then
hopefully right thereafter you can
practice the Luxio Davina okay so that's
basically what we did tomorrow so is
that more time we'll have a slightly
shorter set and I will do the Lexi Oh
Davina again with you I will I will
exemplify it for you again and then
we'll review it one more time on
Thursday and then you you that should be
enough so you get some momentum going
okay I think that's everything we need
for this morning's review well now sit
we're going to sit for again for 15
minutes and then we'll have a little bit
of time for Q&A at the end so please get
your posture ready please make sure that
you set your cones to do not disturb we
will begin when I say begin begin
you
so they come out of your practice trying
as best you can to integrate really
cultivated any practice with your
everyday consciousness and cognition
perhaps by reciting the five promises to
yourself
okay we have time for a couple of
questions my reminder that Tuesday and
Thursday are shorter days Osteen
Silverstone how often do you not
recommend doing Alexio davina I
recommend I mean I do it every day and I
find it is one of those things that
helps to in help me integrate so it's an
extension of the promising suppose we
integrate what I cultivated in my
practice the more comprehensive vision
worldview way of being tried practicing
every day if you can I think it's the
kind of thing that traditionally has
been practiced on a daily basis and I've
not heard of any sort of negative
effects of practicing it daily and and
what I've heard is that when you
practice daily it starts to gain new
momentum so you get to you not only get
the synth Amata between the poetry and
the prose you get the symptom at affirm
yesterday's reading in today's reading
going into tomorrow's reading so you get
the three ten seasons in thematic the
past present and future and you know the
two types of text and since the matter
that's what happens for me in fact so I
recommend that so one more question this
is from pleasure of doubt during after
the meeting Chris's you said that Alexa
Davina was to be done as a group in this
way you model how should we do it in
group setting and I was on the discord
server and entering Bret's question last
night
excellent excellent oh my gosh excellent
time on tier sort server I really
recommend getting involved there so as I
said there what you want to do then is
get into a group one person will do the
reading and the recitation everybody
practices first silently to themselves
as they're doing the recitation has done
aloud but everybody does the all of the
stages individually and then you do
something that's sort of starts to merge
with the Ilocos everybody indicates what
they
from it what they resonated from it and
then you try to get you know a resonance
between the various perspectives and
takes in the sense of everybody is
trying to afford everybody going deeper
seeing more from the text opening it up
really affording a more comprehensive
and expanding field of transformation
and transcendence for everybody so
that's how you would practice it
collectively and it should be practiced
both individually and collectively
optimally collectively and what I mean
is you'll get the optimal experience
usually collectively because I say then
that the the the Alexio Davina bleeds
into a diello ghost and if you want to
know what the Ilocos means to check out
a lot of the voices with four V Keys
when discussing this or to some of the
discs another the group for the four of
us myself Christopher musty petrol guys
10 seconds or hall where we're trying to
exemplify that so that's how I would
answer that question that's all we have
time for for today thank you as always
for joining thank you so much saying uh
the way you guys are building a vibrant
and vital Sangha really really fantastic
keep it up keep it up thank you my dear
friend and techno major Marv was behind
the scenes working his magic all the
time and my beloved son Jason who's
always there taking care of
troubleshooting things that need to be
done here please subscribe to the
channel to be notified of the next video
on the channel you'll find the lectures
here is awakening from the meeting
crisis that the discussion deal will go
series voices with verve a key both of
them are pursuing these topics in
greater depth and expansion and
development invite others who might
benefit by sharing this series with them
to help as many people as possible
during these difficult times as I
mentioned there's an excellent discord
server Brett is usually here during the
sit there's a group on the discord
server that are sitting they meet
afterwards and talk about it I know some
of you have been going onto the
disparate server I strongly recommend
you do that there's a link that will be
provided in the description of the notes
of this video
reminder we're doing this every weekday
morning at 9:30 Eastern Time there's the
general Q&A every third Friday of the
and I believe that's it for today so
please remember continuity more
important than quantity of practice
there is no enemy worse than your own
mind and body no friend and no ally no
true companion better than your own mind
and body take care everyone I'll see you
tomorrow